{
	"cards": [
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-29-tag-multiple-choice-card-1",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"head tilt-chin lift maneuver.",
					"jaw-thrust maneuver.",
					"head tilt-neck lift maneuver.",
					"tongue-jaw lift maneuver."
				],
				"question": "When opening the airway of a patient with a suspected spinal injury, you should use the:",
				"source": "See Patient Assessment"
			},
			"back": "jaw-thrust maneuver."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-29-tag-multiple-choice-card-2",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"lateral immobilization has been applied.",
					"the patient adamantly denies neck pain.",
					"it causes a problem managing the airway.",
					"sensory and motor functions remain intact."
				],
				"question": "Once a cervical collar has been applied to a patient with a possible spinal injury, it should not be removed unless:",
				"source": "See Patient Assessment"
			},
			"back": "it causes a problem managing the airway."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-29-tag-multiple-choice-card-3",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"might lose sensation below the level of the injury.",
					"often loses motor function on one side of the body.",
					"will likely be paralyzed from the neck down.",
					"most commonly has a palpable spinal deformity."
				],
				"question": "When a patient experiences a severe spinal injury, he or she:",
				"source": "See Patient Assessment"
			},
			"back": "might lose sensation below the level of the injury."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-29-tag-multiple-choice-card-4",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"involves physical injury to the brain tissue.",
					"usually does not cause a loss of consciousness.",
					"does not cause pressure within the skull.",
					"results from a laceration to the brain tissue."
				],
				"question": "In contrast to a cerebral concussion, a cerebral contusion:",
				"source": "See Head Injuries"
			},
			"back": "involves physical injury to the brain tissue."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-29-tag-multiple-choice-card-5",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"brain and spinal cord.",
					"cerebellum and brain.",
					"cerebrum and meninges.",
					"meninges and spinal cord."
				],
				"question": "The central nervous system (CNS) is composed of the:",
				"source": "See Anatomy and Physiology"
			},
			"back": "brain and spinal cord."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-29-tag-multiple-choice-card-6",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"Increasing the patient’s body temperature",
					"30-degree elevation of the head",
					"Supine with the legs elevated",
					"Maintaining the SpO2 at 90%"
				],
				"question": "Which of the following interventions may be used to help reduce intracranial pressure?",
				"source": "See Patient Assessment"
			},
			"back": "30-degree elevation of the head"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-29-tag-multiple-choice-card-7",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"thyroxine.",
					"epinephrine.",
					"aldosterone.",
					"insulin."
				],
				"question": "The hormone responsible for the actions of the sympathetic nervous system is:",
				"source": "See Anatomy and Physiology"
			},
			"back": "epinephrine."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-29-tag-multiple-choice-card-8",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"anxiety and restlessness.",
					"hypotension and nosebleed.",
					"tachycardia and diaphoresis.",
					"nausea and ringing in the ears."
				],
				"question": "Signs and symptoms that might be found in a patient who has experienced a concussion include:",
				"source": "See Head Injuries"
			},
			"back": "nausea and ringing in the ears."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-29-tag-multiple-choice-card-9",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"pia mater.",
					"dura mater.",
					"gray mater.",
					"arachnoid mater."
				],
				"question": "The tough, fibrous outer meningeal layer is called the:",
				"source": "See Anatomy and Physiology"
			},
			"back": "dura mater."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-29-tag-multiple-choice-card-10",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"Sensory",
					"Autonomic",
					"Somatic",
					"Central"
				],
				"question": "What part of the nervous system controls the body’s voluntary activities?",
				"source": "See Anatomy and Physiology"
			},
			"back": "Somatic"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-29-tag-multiple-choice-card-11",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"central",
					"somatic",
					"autonomic",
					"peripheral"
				],
				"question": "The _________ nervous system consists of 31 pairs of spinal nerves and 12 pairs of cranial nerves.",
				"source": "See Anatomy and Physiology"
			},
			"back": "peripheral"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-29-tag-multiple-choice-card-12",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"are found supine and have stable vital signs.",
					"require prompt extrication from an automobile.",
					"are sitting in their car and are clinically unstable.",
					"are in a sitting position and are clinically stable."
				],
				"question": "A short backboard or vest-style immobilization device is indicated for patients who:",
				"source": "See Preparation for Transport"
			},
			"back": "are in a sitting position and are clinically stable."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-29-tag-multiple-choice-card-13",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"weak.",
					"rapid.",
					"slow.",
					"irregular."
				],
				"question": "You should be most suspicious that a patient has experienced a significant head injury if his or her pulse is:",
				"source": "See Patient Assessment"
			},
			"back": "slow."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-29-tag-multiple-choice-card-14",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"venous lacerations that occur within the brain.",
					"bleeding between the skull and dura mater.",
					"bleeding between the dura mater and brain.",
					"an injury caused by a damaged cerebral artery."
				],
				"question": "An epidural hematoma is most accurately defined as:",
				"source": "See Head Injuries"
			},
			"back": "bleeding between the skull and dura mater."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-29-tag-multiple-choice-card-15",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"head",
					"waist",
					"lower extremities",
					"chest"
				],
				"question": "When placing a patient onto a long backboard, the EMT at the patient’s _________ is in charge of all patient movements.",
				"source": "See Preparation for Transport"
			},
			"back": "head"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-29-tag-multiple-choice-card-16",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"spinal canal.",
					"intervertebral disc.",
					"vertebral arch.",
					"vertebral body."
				],
				"question": "The spinal cord is encased in and protected by the:",
				"source": "See Anatomy and Physiology"
			},
			"back": "spinal canal."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-29-tag-multiple-choice-card-17",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"a pulse that is rapid and thready.",
					"a decreased level of consciousness.",
					"an abnormally low blood pressure.",
					"decreased sensation in the extremities."
				],
				"question": "The most reliable sign of a head injury is:",
				"source": "See Patient Assessment"
			},
			"back": "a decreased level of consciousness."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-29-tag-multiple-choice-card-18",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"brain stem.",
					"cerebrum.",
					"cerebellum.",
					"medulla."
				],
				"question": "Coordination of balance and body movement is controlled by the:",
				"source": "See Anatomy and Physiology"
			},
			"back": "cerebellum."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-29-tag-multiple-choice-card-19",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"basilar skull fractures.",
					"nondisplaced skull fractures.",
					"linear skull fractures.",
					"depressed skull fractures."
				],
				"question": "The frontal and parietal bones of the skull are especially susceptible to:",
				"source": "See Head Injuries"
			},
			"back": "depressed skull fractures."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-29-tag-multiple-choice-card-20",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"the direct patient carry.",
					"the clothes drag.",
					"the use of a scoop stretcher.",
					"the four-person log roll."
				],
				"question": "The ideal procedure for moving an injured patient from the ground to a backboard is:",
				"source": "See Preparation for Transport"
			},
			"back": "the four-person log roll."
		}
	],
	"category": {
		"value": "chapter-29",
		"label": "Chapter 29"
	},
	"tags": [
		{
			"value": "multiple-choice",
			"label": "Multiple Choice"
		}
	]
}